# **Andri Suryono**

Klaten, Central Java | Portofolio | Linkedin | +6285878183521 | andri.jobs06@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

I'm a graduate of informatics engineering with 5 years experience as an IT staff. Have an interest in programming and currently have completed a bootcamp course at Eduwork with the Mern Stack class and create several projects. Have an experienced to create or develop programmes with PHP programming language, My Sql database, and MERN STACK (Mongo DB, Express JS, React JS, and Node JS). Currently looking for Full Stack Developer, Backend Developer, Front End Developer positions

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Eduwork Yogyakarta

Full Stack Mern - (Intership Project)

Aug 2023 - Oct 2023

- Developed a full stack food store application and achieved 80% feature completion rate in 15 days, using MERN stack (MongoDB, Express Js, React, Node Js).
- Designed databases for products, users, addresses, carts, invoices, categories with 90% accuracy. and orders within 5 days by using MongoDb and Mongoose ODM.
- Implemented secure user authentication and authorization, reducing unauthorized access using JWT, bcrypt
- Created a news application with live search feature and integration with News API with 90% accuracy rate within 2 days. Tools used: React, React Bootrsrap.
- Created a Hijja Store Home Page from the specified ui/ux list and integrate from the systemtoko.com API in less than 7 days. Tools used: React, React Bootstrap, Axios.

### PT. Sinar Klaten Makmur

Klaten, Central Java

Staff IT - (Contract)

Apr 2022 - Jul 2023

- Developed a Packing-Shipment Scan System for the next garment production application project. The system is 100% integratable, by adjusting database fields and master data.
- Created a system design, database and deployment stage for the Garment Production Application within 1 week. Tools Ms. Visio, Excel, Heidi Sql.
- Completed the 1st stage of deploy, bundle record system. Efficiency of creation time 80% from before. Equalized the print out report, added barcode and gr code on the ticket.
- Completed the 2nd stage of deployment, created production scan transactions. Making production data management systemised. By adding work processes that run in the system.
- Completed the final deploy stage, customized reports, added features & modules. The result is a user-friendly system. Using PHP, MYSQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap.

### PT. FGX INDONESIA

Klaten, Central Java

Staff IT - (Contract)

Oct 2020 - Mar 2022

- Created system design, and database for Packing-Shipment Barcode Scan Application, within 1 week. With Microsoft. Visio tools, and phpmyadmin & Heidi Sql
- Complete the Coding Stage of the Packing-Shipment Barcode Scan Application, within 1 month until it can be tried and errored, using PHP and Mysql DB.
- Implement the Scan Barcode Packing-Shipment programme to users, within 2 weeks, provide assistance to users and trial error the system to improve the system.
- Adding validation in the system, the results can minimize the passing of wrong barcode paste up to 95% by adding a validation schema that studies the problems in the field.

• Adding Custom Report and packinglist The result system from the report side is easy to understand. By creating a report display according to user and management requests.

### **CERTIFICATION & BOOTCAMP**

Eduwork Online, ID MERN STACK Aug 2023 – Oct 2023

- Created repository to manage project source code and learn best practices in collaborative software development using Git
- Learned to built user interfaces for 2 weeks using Framework ReactJS
- Learned to make HTTP requests to the server, which is useful for communicating with the backend with a JavaScript library using Axios
- Learned for creating application servers using Node.js as a JavaScript server-side runtime and Express.js as a web framework
- Learned to manage and interact with databases with sequelize on MySQL and Mongoose on MongoDB
- Learned Rest Full API which is useful for exchanging data between the client side and the server or from the Frontend side to the Backend.

### **EDUCATION**

## Universitas Widya Dharma

Klaten, Cemtral Java Sep 2013 – Oct 2017

S1 - Informatics Engineering

GPA 3.4

- Undergraduate Thesis: Academic Information System Using Php at Mts N Srebegan
- I learnt Web programming languages from **HTML**, **CSS**, **PHP**, **Javascript** and learnt MY SQL database which supported my work at my old workplace.

### SKILLS, INTERESTS, & LANGUAGES

Technical Skills: React.js | Node.js | Express.js | My SQL | MongoDB | HTML | CSS |

 $Javascript \mid PHP \mid Bootstrap \mid Tailwind \mid Restfull \; API \mid Git \mid Postman \mid Vs \; Code$ 

**Soft Skills:** Problem Solving | Time Management | Critical Thinking | Inovatif |

Communication

Interests: Full Stack Developer, Backend Developer, Front End Developer Language: Indonesian (Native), English (Beginner), Javanesse (Native)

## **PROJECTS**

Point Of Sale Sep 2023

Details: A system that can support sales transactions, purchases, product management and digital transaction reports at a restaurant or cafe.

Tools: React.JS, Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB, CSS, Boostrap

Github: Repository Frontend | Repository Backend

Demo: <a href="https://pos-sejamcafe.vercel.app/">https://pos-sejamcafe.vercel.app/</a>

## FE Homepage Hijja Store

Sep 2023

Home Page E-Commerce Hijja Store created based on the UI/UX design that has been provided Eduwork <u>Link Pixma</u>. And Restfull API From link <u>Sistem Toko</u>.

Tools : React JS | Bootstrap | Javascript | HTML | CSS

Github: https://github.com/andry06/hijja-store

Demo: https://hijja-store.vercel.app/

## **Slicing UI Desain Home Page Travlog**

November 2023

Slicing travel blog home page from ui / ux design for Travlog in figma. by making it responsive display for 3 views desktop, tablet, mobile.

Tools : React JS | Tailwind CSS | HTML | CSS | Javascript

Figma: Link design Figma

Github: <a href="https://github.com/andry06/slicing-design-travel-web">https://github.com/andry06/slicing-design-travel-web</a>

Demo: <a href="https://slicing-travel-web.vercel.app/">https://slicing-travel-web.vercel.app/</a>

### **Production Garment System**

Jul 2022 - Jun 2023

Details: A system that supports the management of garment production data from order data recap, pre-production, bundle record system, monitoring production output and stock of goods in each department from cutting to finishgood process, and there is a shipment process to generate packinglist of finished goods sent.

Running: PT. Sinar Klaten Makmur

Tools: PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS Bootstrap
Demo: Demo Aplikasi Produksi Garment Sistem

### REFERENCE

Name : Ringga Gustavino

Company : Eduwork

Position : Mentor - Mern Stack

Contact : 081296001282

Name : Rahmatullah

Company : PT. Sinar Klaten Makmur

Position : Supervisor IT Contact : 08988967889